Stephen F. Dobbs

Crowd TD / Technical Animator / CG Generalist

Summary

Film and Television studio CGI veteran with feature film work experience as a Crowd TD, Technical Animator, CG Generalist, and live-action camera Integratior. Experience on set. Features VFX bidding Clean effective coding abilities.

Skills

Maya, Nuke, Houdini, MotionBuilder, Golaem, Arnold, V-Ray, mentalray, Adobe CC, ZBrush, 3DEqualizer, Unity, Resolve, MeshLab, Cubase (many others)

Python, MEL, Perl, C#, C++, Javascript, HTML5, CSS3, PHP, MySQL, Unix/Irix/Linux Shell

Education

Berklee College of Music Art Institute of Atlanta SGI Silicon Studio

Contact Information

Stephen F. Dobbs www.linkedin.com/in/themanfromtomorrow











Experience

Blur Studio Culver City, CA 2019 Supervising Crowd TD - Assets, Simulation, Pipeline Integration, Code.

Ultimately responsible for Golaem Crowd asset creation, performances, problem solving, and pipeline integration (XSI|Maya-Golaem|3DSMAX) for: "League of Legends 2020 Start".

Used software tools and experience to effectively create the illusion of intelligent quadruped creatures swarming complex surface environments, stalking prey, and reacting to physical forces (explosions). Wrote custom phython code for quick animation retargeting of MoCap data (removing MotionBuilder from the equation). Solved a studio technical issue that had stymied production since before my arrival. Submitted the "zero length" spine bug to Golaem.

Worked closely with the animation director to develop a sense of creature motion and behavior characteristics, and while balancing locomotion cycles for aesthetic stride motion. Communicated clip cycle requests to animators. Communicated specific flexible "prop attachment point" joint chain needs with the rigging department

Participated in meetings with department heads to define/clarify processes and methods for moving the highest quality assets throught crowd systems and delivering optimized caches for scene assembly(final integration and rendering).

Primal Screen Atlanta, GA 2017 - 2018 Supervising Crowd TD - Assets, Simulation, Pipeline Integration, Code.

Soley responsible for the creation of all crowd assets and the entire crowd shot pipeline Built multiple character rigs(Maya) featuring dozens of skinned assets, including props, wardrobe accessories, and blend shapes while maintaining strict requirements for Golaem Crowd agents. Setup crowd agent properties and behavior trees. Setup and re-targeted animation across character rigs to convert motions into clips usable by crowd agents. Completed crowd layouts and simulations for 95% of the film "Elf Pets: Santa's St Bernards Save Christmas".

Exported alembic environment, character, and camera data from all shots(70+) that required crowds. Setup and prepared all crowd shots including cleaning up imported alembic and camera data. Conformed V-Ray shaders on all crowd assets to resolve naming conflicts and optimize linear lighting workflows. Supported 100% of all crowd issues and problem solving including rendering.

Wrote python code that allowed animators to blindly create organized playblast files to assist editorial. Wrote a python hook into Shotgun to override default namespace conventions on imported Maya assets. Wrote preliminary python code for XGEN crowd integration. Wrote python code for crowd rig automation and general crowd support.

Freelance 2014 - 2017

CG Generalist - Crowd TD, Character TD, Technical Animator, Code.

Remote multi-role CG Technical Artist.

Highlights include:

2016 - "Star Trek Beyond" (Kelvin Optical/Bad Robot - Santa Monica, CA)
Anamorphic camera integration, geometric deformations, code.

2015 - "Woodlawn" (Remote)

Crowd R&D/Setup/Simulation. MoCap, Modeling, Render Setup, Shaders, Matchmove, Code. Credited with three titles: Crowd TD, Additional Crowd Animation, and Match Move Artist. Solely responsible for show crowd pipeline and all crowd R&D including working out character performances as well as adding new agent texture, model, and animation assets to the golaem packaged standard crowd characters. Generated new agent cycle animation inside MotionBuilder using a mix of hand keying, editing existing mocap, and generated mocap using MS Kinect. Created new agent props with associated cycle animations and textures. Created agent behavior trees for numerous activities including proper sit-to stand and stand-to-sit translations.

R&D responsibilities included working out anamorphic lens issues, plate over-scan values, writing code to import point cloud data, and modeling precise geo for camera integration.

2014 - "Sleepy Hollow" (Remote)

Character tracking for head removal on Fox Television Episodic.

Stephen F. Dobbs

Crowd TD / Technical Animator / CG Generalist

Awards & Organizations



Cinefex Magazine #77 article mention, Contributing team member of Oscar nominated 'visual effects' motion pictures - 'Starship Troopers' and 'Snow White and the Huntsman', member of Southeastern Filmmakers, former member of ASIFA-Hollywood, former student member of AES. President of highschool photography club, Recipient of Principal's Award for Sculpting.

Filmography (VFX)

Star Trek Beyond Woodlawn R.I.P.D. Snow White and t

Snow White and the Huntsman

Shrek2

Sum of All Fears

Scooby Doo

Cats & Dogs

Babe, Pig in the City

Entropy

Starship Troopers

Cable Guy

Contact

Ghost and the Darkness

(One-offs for;)

Harry Potter
Planet of the Apes
Summer of Sam

(and many more)

Contact Information

Stephen F. Dobbs www.linkedin.com/in/themanfromtomorrow

Experience (Continued)

Rhythm & Hues El Segundo, CA 2011 - 2012

Technical Director - (Artist/CGI)

Created extremely accurate low-poly models with clean topology from dense lidar scans of practical sets for use in matchmoving/animation/lighting pipelines. Built lens databases from grid plates, established world scale, and matchmoved shots. Moderated teleconferences and assisted fellow artists daily at international studios. Wrote code to assist tasks.Completed work on Motion Pictures and National Commercial Spots.

Highlights include "R.I.P.D." and "Snow White and the Huntsman".

Freelance Augusta, GA 2005 - 2010

CG Generalist - Digital Artist, Code.

Performed tasks as a CG Generalist in a local broadcast market. Skills development.

PDI/DreamWorks Redwood City, CA 2003 - 2004

Technical Animator - (Artist/CGI)

Created and animated shot specific deformation rigs to perform prop animation, deform baked geo for effect, and correct geometric interpenetration. Setup and executed rigid body physics simulations. Setup and simulated cloth garments. Wrote code to assist tasks and fulfill specific assignments.

Completed work on nearly 200 shots for the Motion Picture "Shrek 2".

Rhythm & Hues Studios Los Angeles, CA 2001 - 2002 Technical Animator - (Artist/CGI)

Organized, scheduled, developed workflow technique, and managed the matchmove team for the motion picture 'Sum of all Fears'. Converted spherical lens data into anamorphic data. Used witness and reference images for photogrametry. Setup constraints and minor rigs for character-to-character interactions, character-to-ground plane interactions and dog tag animation. Completed character fur simulations. Meticulously and accurately animated gross animal motion and camera parameters to match live-action plates. Used deformation tools to conform geometry to fit specific animal facial shapes in the live-action plates. Successfully assisted with Features Bidding. Completed work on Motion Pictures and National Commercial Spots.

Highlights include "Sum of all Fears", "Scooby Doo", and "Cats & Dogs".

Rhythm & Hues Studios Los Angeles, CA 1998 - 1999 Technical Director - Supervising Matchmove Lead, Code

Meticulously and accurately animated gross animal motion and camera parameters to match live-action plates. Used deformation tools to conform geometry to fit specific animal facial shapes in the live-action plates. Helped software dept. make improvements to R&H's proprietary software. Bid matchmoving man hours for several feature films. Supervised matchmoving effort and trained new hires for "Babe: Pig in the City". Lead MMTD for "Entropy" and "Summer of Sam". Supervised MM stage setup for a talking mouse in a J.C. Penny's commercial. Other commercials include spots for LAZBOY and Dodge Neon.

Highlights include 'Babe: Pig in the City', 'Entropy', and 'Summer of Sam'.

Sony Pictures Imageworks Culver City, CA Technical Director - Matchmove, Data I/O, Code.

1996 - 1998

Matchmoved motion control miniatures to live-action plates using Softlmage and Alias/Wave-front Advanced Visualizer for the feature film "Starship Troopers". Tracked image features using Alias/Wavefront Composer. On-set data gathering responsibilities included traditional measurement methods, use of a Nikon Total Station with reflection targets, and retrieval of Kuper motion control data. Wrote scripts to import stage MoCo data into Softlmage. Created models from total station survey data. Messaged, reshaped, and otherwise manipulated camera and lens curve data by hand to produce aesthetic motion

Inferno Technical Assistant. Responsible for file and image I/O for Inferno/Flame/Flint suites, Dataview and Sirius video archiving, and shell scripting. Completed work on Motion Pictures and Television Episodics.

Highlights include "Starship Troopers", "Cable Guy", and "Ghost in the Darkness".